SHANTHI ACHARYA

Lead Product Designer

shanthi.s.acharya@gmail.com | 510-226-7914 Portfolio: http://shanthiacharya.com/portfolio/index.html

Talented senior designer of user-experience design with the proven know-how to combine creativity, end user focus and business goals resulting in world-class design solutions.

10+ years of success delivering compelling user experience across web and mobile solution for enterprise and consumer brands. Experienced working in agile environments applying design-thinking, rapid prototyping approaches and collaborating with global stakeholders.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ellie Mae | Lead Product Designer | June 2016 – Present

Lead strategy & design efforts for several key next gen initiatives for mortgage enterprise application by collaborating with product management & engineering to create delightful experiences.

- Marketplace: Lead a highly successful 5-day design sprint workshop to create design vision for MVP and drive the future efforts for Ellie Mae marketplace for lenders and partners to leverage the lending platform and create new revenue streams.
- Encompass Next Gen: Leading design efforts for fintech applications with one-click automated service
 ordering, new government loan forms, admin setup and configuration. Co-ordinate with design patterns team
 to make it part of the reusable pattern library.
- AllRegs Online: Lead Responsive redesign of AllRegs website by working with product management, applying usability and customer insights. Revamped outdated UI with new branding and visual refresh that resulted in increased customer confidence and several sales wins.

GE Digital | Staff UX Designer | May 2012 – June 2016

Lead design & research efforts with multi-disciplinary and international teams to deliver compelling user experiences for Industrial Internet Applications for 10 + projects across several GE businesses. Won **5 Above & Beyond awards** for Expertise, Team Collaboration and Imagination in different projects.

- Asset Performance Management (APM): Lead Design efforts for Oil & Gas APM product working with
 external customers in rapid iterative approach delivering designs that won customer confidence and
 satisfaction. Mentored new team members and ramped up on both business and UX goals. Cross team
 collaboration with framework team to achieve product consistency.
- o Lead UX strategy for **Oil & Gas Fleet solution** that provided a holistic view of the customer assets and alarms using web & mobile cloud solutions.
- Seastream Insight: Designed and prototyped an analytics application showcasing visualization capabilities.
- o **Industrial eCommerce:** Developed UX strategy and assets for My Industrial Store, an ecommerce platform that can be leveraged across GE businesses. Lead the design efforts producing wireframes, design patterns and interactive HTML5 prototype.
- o **Field Service UX:** Envisioned and prototyped an iOS app that allows field engineers to capture a machine part picture and submit a part request to speed up the parts ordering process for GE Power Conversion business.
- Controls Convergence UX: Worked on several key initiatives under the GE Controls product line. Developed UX strategy, storyboards and wireframes for a Mobile application for Field Service engineers to perform their workflow of commissioning an Oil & Gas site.

Western Digital | Senior UX Designer | Jun 2010 – May2012

Lead designer for 5+ projects at Western Digital Branded Products Group to deliver innovative design solutions for WD networked devices.

- O WD Media Library: Delivered Information architecture, task flows, wireframes and interactive prototype for rich media web UI for WD home storage devices. Established UCD process in the team and guided the user researcher on usability study. Worked with Agile development team to deliver designs and coded the front end for several areas.
- WD TV: Designed screens and interactions for WD TV Live Hub media player to integrate with Mobile devices. Delivered task flows and UI specs and worked with product management and engineering to ensure best user experience.
- o **WD Mobile Apps:** Created and refined UI screens for WD Photos, a photo viewer app available in iTunes App store and Android market. Included several usability fixes for existing UI and created interactions and mockups for new features. Created concepts for WD 2 go mobile app, a file browser to view contents from networked devices.
- O WD Personal Cloud: Created flows and wireframes for WD 2go.com, a web based portal that provides easy remote access to WD networked devices. Designed screens and interaction for remote access integration and worked with several product teams to integrate this central feature for WD personal cloud products.

UX Consultant | Nov 2009 – May 2010

• Kno Inc: Translated concepts and wireframes into prototype requirements and technology selection. Created production quality interactive prototype for touch screen based tablet device targeted at education market using Adobe Flex. Worked with user researchers in planning and conducting usability studies with the prototype and provided design feedback to the team.

IBM | UX Designer Intern | Mar 2008 – Oct 2009

 IBM Mashup Center: Worked on Design & Usability testing of IBM Mashup Center Catalog to provide better integration experience across different components of Mashup center. Worked end-to-end from concept, prototypes, usability testing and working with development.

Intel | Senior Software Engineer | Oct 1999 – Mar 2008

 Benchmark software development and Application Performance Study on Intel processor performance with focus on user experience assessment and performance data analysis.

EDUCATION

- O M.S. Human Factors, San Jose State University.
- o M.S. Computer Science, California State University, Hayward
- O Udacity Senior Web Developer Nanodegree & React Nanodegree